<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Ed Beach (Firaxis Games) -->

-<GameData>


	-<LocalizedText>

		<!--CIVILIZATION-->



		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_NAME">

			<Text>Maya</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_DESCRIPTION">

			<Text>Mayan Empire</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_ADJECTIVE">

			<Text>Mayan</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_DESCRIPTION_JFD_CIVILIZATION">

			<Text>Mayan Civilization</Text>

		</Row>

		<!--Pedia-->



		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_LOCATION">

			<Text>Mesoamerica</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_POPULATION">

			<Text>Est. 2 million</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_SIZE">

			<Text>Est. 200,000 sq miles</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_CAPITAL">

			<Text>City-states, none specified</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">

			<Text>The Māori are the group of indigenous Polynesian people of New Zealand (which they called Aotearoa, or the Land of the Long White Cloud). The Māori have settled on New Zealand for nearly three quarters of a millenium, in their isolation they created their own culture and society. The early Māoris formed tribes - influenced from their earlier Polynesian societies, horticulture began to thrive from the importation of flora, and the infamous warrior culture rose into prominence. The arrival of the British in the 17th century set about great change in every aspect of Māori life, initially the Māori adopted and accepted European culture and the two coexisted peacefully. Tensions over the sale of land however led to conflict by the 1860s; social upheaval, battles and foreign epidemics struck the Māori population and caused their numbers to dindle before a recovery in the 20th century.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">

			<Text>New Zealand sits southeast of Australia in the South Pacific Ocean. Formed from tectonic movement, much of New Zealand and its surrounding islands are mountainous and volcanic. The landmasses were formed when the continent of Zealandia - formed roughly 83 million years ago - had sank into the ocean 20 million years ago, leaving the highlands above sea level. The North Island is smaller and less mountainous than the South Island, yet it is more marked by active volcanoes; Mount Ruapehu, the island’s tallest peak is itself an active cone volcano, and Lake Taupo, New Zealand’s largest lake is a caldera, a feature formed from a collapse of the land due to a volcanic eruption.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">

			<Text>Little is known about the Polynesian voyage to New Zealand - the current evidence suggests the ancient Māori first landed and settled on New Zealand at around 1280, and that the heavy presence of female Māori at the time suggests the landing on New Zealand was deliberate.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Archaic period of the Māori describes the first years of settlement, where the tribes - known to the Māori as ‘iwi’ - settled by the woodlands where several species of moa birds once lived. The Māori hunted the moa to such an extent that the moa became extinct in New Zealand during this time, the Archaic period is also known as the ‘Moahunter’ period for this reason. The Otago iwi became the center of Māori cultural development with most of their settlements established within 6 miles of the coast. Intriguingly the period saw a complete lack of weaponry, instead the Archaic period is known for the creation of “reel necklaces” and the hunting of the local birdlife. Apart from birds the Māori diet was rich in seafood, and despite the low life expectancy of the Māori - around 31-32 years - and the hard life of the frontiersmen, the iwi was capable of supporting their injured and infirm.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]By the start of the 16th century the climate had cooled, and around this time a series of large earthquakes struck the South Island. Combined with the extinction of the moa bird, among other food sources, sweeping changes in Māori life developed into the more recognisable customs that defines the Classic period. The Māori created pounamu weapons made from indigenous nephrite jade or bowenite stone in this period. Curved canoes were developed by the Māori, and the fierce warrior culture sprang into action; building hillforts across the islands - the pa, engaging in frequent cannibalism, and controlled some of the largest canoes in history. It was in this moment that contact was first made with Europe.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">

			<Text>Abel Tasman and Captain James Cook are two of the first explorers to discover and land on New Zealand; Tasman in 1642 and Cook in 1769. Initial contact was problematic and in some cases fatal. In the 1780s the Māori meet whaling crews from Europe and America, some of these crews already held Māori. Some South Island crews were nearly entirely Māori. A trickle of convicts escaping Australia, deserters from passing ships, and Christian missionaries added to the European influence over the Māori. In the Boyd Massacre of 1809 the Māori took hostage and killed 66 people in an act of revenge, the cannibalism of these people caused shipping and whaling companies to be wary and to steer clear from New Zealand in following years.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]By 1830 as many as 2000 Europeans were living with the Māori. The Europeans had positions in all parts of Māori society, from slaves serving their masters to high-ranking advisor roles for the iwi chiefs. Some Europeans were prisoners in their new home, others expatriated from their homeland and identified themselves as Māori, they were known to the Māori as Pakeha Māori - literally meaning ‘European Māori’. They were valued as an asset to many iwis as European knowledge and technologies were handed down from Pakeha Māori, most notably firearms. The Māori language was first notated by Thomas Kendall in 1815, five years later Professor Samuel Lee compiled the Māori grammar and vocabulary. The Māori quickly adopted literacy from missionaries. The established colonial government handed free gazettes to the Māori in 1843 called Ko Te Karere O Nui Tireni; it outlined information about colonial law, crimes, explanations and remarks on European customs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Between 1805 and 1840 however, the purchase of muskets by iwis with European contact upset the balance of power, leading to a period of violent inter-tribal warfare known as the Musket Wars. The powerful iwi destroyed their weaker foes and drove the rest out of their homelands. From 100,000 in 1800 the Māori population is said to have dropped between 20% and 50% by 1843; a census in 1856-7 reveals the population then to be 56,049, this is during a time of relative stability in Māori life. However the Musket Wars were not the only contributing factor to the mortality of Māori then, European diseases such as influenza and measles killed an unknown number of Māori, contributed largely by new European settlers who had not performed recent health checks. Pakeha Māori Te Rangi Hiroa documented a respiratory epidemic the Māori called ‘rewharewha’. He recorded that “almost everything, except plague and sleeping sickness have taken their toll on Māori dead.”</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">

			<Text>As the colonies spread further in the 1830s and missionaries became more active, and a growing lawlessness in the colonies themselves, the British Crown accepted requests from missions and chiefs to intervene. However some escaped convicts, seamen, gunrunners and Americans sought to actively work against the British, spreading rumours to the Māori of mistreatment and oppression. Chief Tamati Waka Nene was angry at the colonial government’s disinclination to stop gunrunners from selling weapons to rebels. The French had also begin to take interest in acquiring New Zealand for themselves, they sent French missionaries to spread anti-British sentiment. Despite this Queen Victoria sent Captain William Hobson to negotiate terms for a treaty between Britain and New Zealand. Arriving on February 1840 Hobson set about establishing a treaty with the chiefs of the North Island - the Treaty of Waitangi. Ultimately 500 chiefs and a small collection of Europeans signed the document, only a few chiefs refused to do so, affected by France’s interests these few were Catholic chiefs. The treaty gave the Māori the rights of British subjects as well as a guarantee in tribal autonomy in exchange for British sovereignty.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Even today dispute over the exact terms of the treaty remains, due largely to the Māori translation of the document, translated by Henry and William Williams. Their imperfect Māori and a lack of exactly similar words in the Māori lexicon handicapped them to create an imperfect representation of the terms. Despite this though relations between Britain and the Māori were largely peaceful; the Māori set up shops and businesses, selling and exporting foods and product domestically and internationally. This would not last though, tensions rose as disputes over land purchases and an attempt by the Māori to create what some saw as a rival to the British royalty system led to the New Zealand wars in the 1860s. The wars began when rebel Māori attacked isolated settlers in Taranaki, the major conflicts though were against British forces - including levied troops from Australia and few allied Māori - against numerous Māori iwis opposed to the land sales. While the wars in fact resulted in few deaths on either side of the conflict, the colonies confiscated land as punishment from what were seen as rebellions, in some cases from iwis which took no part in any of the conflicts, though they were almost instantly returned again.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Native Lands Acts of 1862 and 1865 established the Native Land Court, a specialized court that dealt with the ownership of Māori land. This also allowed Māori to sell their lands to both colonial government and private settlers. Subsequent transactions saw nearly all Māori lands sold by 1890, although over time some of these lands were returned to them.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">

			<Text>During the late 19th century, the Māori population started to considerably decline as European colonists settled in New Zealand. In 1840, the population of New Zealand was estimated between 50,000 and 70,000 Māori and 2,000 Europeans, but by 1950 the European population exploded tenfold. In the 1896 census, the Māori numbered 42,113 and paled in comparison to the now more than 700,000 European colonists present on New Zealand. At the same time, it was observed by Professor Ian Poole that female Māori children had a very high chance of death before the age of one. Despite this and the fears that Māori would simply be absorbed into the European populace, the population decline would come to an end in the following decades into the 20th century. By the late 1930s the Māori population was well over 80,000. Many Māori who intermarried with Europeans, and their children, would continue to identify as Māori and keep their culture alive for generations to come. The Māori would also give rise to several successful politicians and a political party, the Young Māori Party, whose goal was to improve the lives of the Māori by blending with European culture while still keeping traditional practices and art alive.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Māori troops took part in both world wars. A pioneer battalion of nearly 3,000 Māori and Pacific islanders were deployed in Egypt and later the Gallipoli peninsula during World War I. Upon their return to New Zealand after the war, the country was struck by a devastating influenza outbreak that killed 4.5 times more Māori than those of European descent. When World War II began, Māori were exempt from being conscripted into the military, but many still enlisted voluntarily. The 28th Māori Battalion consisted of about 3,600 men over the course of the entire war fighting in North Africa, Italy, Crete, and Greece, proving to be formidable soldiers that earned the respect of both Allied and Axis commanders. Over 12,000 other Māori soldiers served among the New Zealand forces outside of the 28th Battalion during the war.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">

			<Text>Since the beginning of the new millennium, the position of Māori within wider New Zealand society has continued to be a contentious topic, and one which contains both tales of triumph and adversity. Disputes which arose as a result of the differing interpretations of the Treaty of Waitangi continue to be a prominent issue both in New Zealand politics and in the judicial system, with a dedicated permanent commission of inquiry established to resolve disputes between Iwi and the New Zealand Government. Multiple political parties have been established around the premise of Māori rights, which alongside dedicated Māori seats in Parliament seek to ensure that Māori have involvement in the government. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Outside politics, Māori culture has also seen a revival in recent years. Many Māori words have been adopted into New Zealand English, with words such as Pakeha (meaning a New Zealander of European ancestry) and Ka Pai (used to express approval of something) are as widely known as any English word amongst the New Zealand population, and are used in everyday English to create a form of the language unique to the island nation (although English words still vastly outnumber Māori ones.) Te Reo Māori is taught in many primary and secondary schools, often alongside Māori cultural activities known as Kapa Haka (which involve learning Māori waiata, or songs, as well as traditional Māori performance activities such as poi or Haka.) Some aspects of Māori culture have been adopted by wider New Zealand society as a representation of the whole country, with often cited examples being Te Rauparaha's Haka, Ka Mate, frequently performed by the All Blacks (New Zealand's Rugby Union team) and the Māori waiata Pokarekare Ana, written during or shortly after World War One by a Māori soldier. Māori is one of three official languages of New Zealand, alongside English and New Zealand Sign Language, one of the core reasons for its prevalence in schools. Many place names also have Māori names alongside their English ones, such as New Zealand's highest mountain Aoraki / Mt. Cook, or the popular tourist destination of Piopiotahi / Milford Sound. Similarly, both main islands of New Zealand have official Māori names alongside their English ones, Te Ika a Maui and Te Wai Pounamu for the North and South Islands respectively. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] However, the Māori population remains to an extent marginalised in New Zealand society, and is often over-represented in crime statistics and under-represented in school achievement rates. While only 14% of New Zealand's population identify as Māori, saome 50% of the prison population is Māori. Māori also have higher levels of substance abuse and addiction than Pakeha, and on average have a life expectancy roughly 7 years shorter than that of Pakeha. These are but a few of the issues faced by the modern day Māori population, and which they continue to face on an everyday basis.</Text>

		</Row>

		<!--Trait-->



		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_CALENDAR_ROUNDS_NAME">

			<Text>Calendar Rounds</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_RELIC_ENIG_CALENDAR_ROUNDS_DESCRIPTION">

			<Text>Gain Great Scientist points every time you gain a Eureka or enter a new era.  Holy Sites do not fill a District slot and its buildings grant half their [ICON_FAITH] Faith yield in [ICON_SCIENCE] Science.</Text>

		</Row>

		<!--Citizens-->


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_1">

			<Text>Tane</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_2">

			<Text>Apirana</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_3">

			<Text>Hone</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_4">

			<Text>Tamati</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_5">

			<Text>Wiremu</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_6">

			<Text>Tame</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_7">

			<Text>Tiare</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_8">

			<Text>Ihaia</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MALE_9">

			<Text>Matiu</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_1">

			<Text>Nikora</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_2">

			<Text>Tane</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_3">

			<Text>Tamati</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_4">

			<Text>Rawiri</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_5">

			<Text>Tai</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_6">

			<Text>Rawiri</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_7">

			<Text>Manaia</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_8">

			<Text>Tangaroa</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_9">

			<Text>Manaaki</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_MALE_10">

			<Text>Hemi</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_1">

			<Text>Anika</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_2">

			<Text>Hinewai</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_3">

			<Text>Aroha</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_4">

			<Text>Kora</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_5">

			<Text>Maia</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_6">

			<Text>Amaia</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_7">

			<Text>Tui</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_8">

			<Text>Hana</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_9">

			<Text>Awhina</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_FEMALE_10">

			<Text>Aroha</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_1">

			<Text>Kaia</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_2">

			<Text>Mereana</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_3">

			<Text>Mareikura</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_4">

			<Text>Hinewai</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_5">

			<Text>Wikitoria</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_6">

			<Text>Tiare</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_7">

			<Text>Ria</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_8">

			<Text>Kora</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_9">

			<Text>Anahera</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_CITIZEN_RELIC_ENIG_MAYA_MODERN_FEMALE_10">

			<Text>Aria</Text>

		</Row>

		<!--TAUA-->



		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_UNIT_RELIC_ENIG_MACUAHUITL_NAME">

			<Text>Macuahuitl</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_UNIT_RELIC_ENIG_MACUAHUITL_DESCRIPTION">

			<Text>Mayan unique unit which replaces the Swordsman.  It requires no iron and is cheaper to produce.  Grants science from combat in friendly territory and faith from combat in enemy territory.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_RELIC_ENIG_MACUAHUITL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">

			<Text>A taua is a war party in the tradition of the Māori. Contemporary knowledge of taua is gleaned from missionary observations and writings during the Musket Wars of the early 19th century and the later New Zealand wars. The reason to engage gather a taua may be for reasons of seeking revenge (utu) or seeking compensation for an offence against an individual, community or society (muru).</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_ABILITY_RELIC_ENIG_MACUAHUITL_NAME">

			<Text>Sacrifices of Kulkulkan</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_ABILITY_RELIC_ENIG_MACUAHUITL_DESCRIPTION">

			<Text>Grants science from combat in friendly territory and fatih from combat in enemy territory.</Text>

		</Row>

		<!--PA-->



		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_RELIC_ENIG_CARACOL_NAME">

			<Text>Caracol</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_RELIC_ENIG_CARACOL_DESCRIPTION">

			<Text>A district unique to the Māori for military facilities and growth. Replaces the Encampment.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+1 [ICON_FOOD] Food when built adjacent to a Farm or Plantation. +15% combat experience for all melee and ranged Units trained in this city.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_RELIC_ENIG_CARACOL_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">

			<Text>The word pā can refer to any Māori village or defensive settlement, but often refers to hill forts – fortified settlements with palisades and defensive terraces – and also to fortified villages. In Māori culture, a great pā represented the mana (prestige or power) and strategic ability of an iwi (tribe or tribal confederacy), as personified by a rangatira (chieftain). Pā are located in various defensible locations around the territory (rohe) of an iwi to protect fertile plantation sites and food supplies.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_RELIC_ENIG_CARACOL_HOLY_SITE">

			<Text>+{1_num} [ICON_SCIENCE] Science from the adjacent Holy Site.</Text>

		</Row>


		-<Row Language="en_US" Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_RELIC_ENIG_CARACOL_CITY_CENTER">

			<Text>+{1_num} [ICON_SCIENCE] Food from the adjacent City Center.</Text>

		</Row>

	</LocalizedText>

</GameData>
